Shima-san, are you okay?
I believe I told you, Young Su,
that our bodies constantly deplete,
like a spirit's.
I know there are three of
you Ryuzus that alternate,
but since you were removed from
the rotation, there's no replacement.
I cannot say for certain that I will
last until Emilia-sama returns.
So I will say what must be said.
You don't hafta push yourself like that!
The healthy old hag right
here can take your—
That's too confusing!
Call them Old Shi and Old Ryu!
Besides, that won't work.
Only Shima-san can tell us this.
Yes, only I, one who has entered the graveyard
and attempted the trial, can speak of it.
It is about the memories of Ryuzu Meyer,
the progenitor we copies are derived from.
It happened before this place
became known as the Sanctuary.
The beginning of this unknown memory
was a young girl with a lovely face,
skin as white as snow, and pale blue eyes.
What is it, I suppose?
Look at me that way all you want,
but I won't give you anything.
Hmph. Silent again.
What a boring, cowardly girl you are, I suppose.
Beatrice, why the attitude?
Echidna-sama...
Did I teach you to behave that way?
Uh... Y-You're mistaken, Mother!
I didn't do anything!
It's just...
This girl was...
I see.
Then why don't we hear what she has to say?
Wha... um... well...
Yes. I'm very sorry.
I saw her standing there,
looking so wistful,
and I was captivated.
Captivated, eh?
Beatrice, you heard Ryuzu.
Mew...
It would be inaccurate to call you childish,
since you are a child,
but your attitude lacks tolerance.
It's true that you are special,
but not so that you can look down on others.
I'm sorry to startle you.
This is Beatrice.
She is like a daughter to me.
I'm not "like" your daughter!
I am your daughter, I suppose!
Yes, well, there you have it.
I believe she'll be accompanying
me here often from now on.
Please do be kind to her.
Y-Yes, you can count on me, Echidna-sama.
I don't need her.
I'm just fine on my own.
That was how the two girls met.
After that, the witch and her daughter
visited the settlement occasionally.
Why are you just standing there, I suppose?
I see you're as dull as ever.
Beatrice-sama...
Mother is having a discussion inside.
She'll be back when she finishes,
so hurry up and put that irritating
laundry in the basket, I suppose.
O-Of course.
Excuse me.
Um, Beatrice-sama?
It's nothing. Just killing time, I suppose.
Beatrice-sama...
U-Um, if you don't mind,
would you help me fold the laundry?
What?!
If it's too much for you to handle alone,
I suppose I have no choice but to help you.
Huh?
I won't say it again, I suppose!
Well, get going, then! Let's go, I suppose!
U-Um, if you don't mind, would
you carry a little bit of it?
Listen...
Don't go pushing your luck.
Just this much, I suppose.
So when the witch had
business to attend to,
the young girl would spend
her time with Ryuzu Meyer.
You, there. Pardon me.
I believe Echidna-sama is here.
Have you seen her?
What?
M-Mathers-sama!
I'm not fond of being addressed
by my family name.
Would you just call me Roswaal?
Hang on a minute!
Beatrice was in the Sanctuary?
And Roswaal, too?
More accurately, that was the Roswaal-sama
of several generations ago.
But it sounds as if Beatrice-sama
hasn't changed.
I'm more interested in the witch.
I know this is the Witch of
Greed's experimental facility,
but I've never actually heard her story.
Really? You never met the
witch in the trials?
I only went in to settle a score.
I didn't meet the witch.
But when you say that, it sounds like you...
Have you met the Witch of Greed, Barusu?
Yeah.
I see.
To one who was not alive during that time,
the witch may indeed seem
quite out of reach.
Of course, even my memories
are those of another.
I do not know her personally.
Seeing one who looks identical
to me saying that
makes me feel as if I've
gone mad. How frightening.
I feel like I'm listening to clones
telling dark jokes.
Beatrice-sama is an exceedingly common
presence in Ryuzu Meyer's memories.
They had quite the heartwarming friendship.
Go ahead and finish the story.
The Sanctuary seemed so
peaceful on the surface,
so what happened?
It collapsed.
Then the true reason for the
Sanctuary's existence came along.
The true reason... for its existence?
Sin Archbishop of the Witch's Cult,
representing Greed...
Regulus Corneas.
A Sin Archbishop of the Witch's Cult?
What are you doing here?
I was assured that no one could get
involved with this forest except me!
Assured?
I think you just made up that
rule and assured yourself.
And now you're trying to force
other people to go along with it?
Pretty cocky for some worthless spirit.
If you dislike the rule,
then talk it over with the church!
Why have you come here?!
Because...
I ordered him to.
What's the matter, Bishop Romanée-Conti?
Why...
Why are you here?!
Regulus Corneas! Why is she here?!
Hah! She came here of her own will.
Why are you blaming everything on me?
You got something against me?
Bishop Corneas, he is simply confused.
Try not to criticize him so much.
Now, bring the key and seal here,
so that the Witch's Cult can fulfill
its long-cherished desire.
Pandora!
Oh?
Enjoy being skewered!
And apologize to my brother and his wife!
Now begone forever!
Hey, come on.
You weren't even aiming anywhere near me,
but you used an attack that
you knew would hit me, too?
That's the same as trampling on my life,
on my existence, on my authority,
on my humanity itself, isn't it?
Fortuna-sama!
Please take Emilia-sama and leave here.
Mother...
Emilia...
Worry not.
I would not remain here without a plan.
I swear I'll come back to help you!
I swear it!
Geuse!
Keeping the trial in mind,
you should be following yourself, no?
What will you do?
Hey, that was pretty admirable.
But who gave you permission
to let them get away?
That's a violation of my actions
and authority, isn't it?
Say what you will.
If it means risking my very existence,
I cannot allow the two of
you to get past this point!
Wait, you're not gonna...
I do not have the knowledge
to adapt to this.
For that reason, I have done nothing but
hold it since I was entrusted with it.
But it was meant for a moment such as this!
Bishop Petelgeuse Romanée-Conti...
Have a good journey.
Please... forgive me...
Flugel-sama!
What an idiot.
Magnificent...
Bishop Regulus Corneas.
Yes?
Here it comes.
I told you...
What you see here is hope.
A great, unforgettable debt to the
people who made me what I am.
So now...
If I am worthy of spitting up blood...
What do you see with those crimson eyes,
Bishop Romanée-Conti?
Love.
I will not let you pursue those two.
I will not allow you to get past me!
Geuse, what... What did you do?!
A splendid show of your resolve,
Bishop Petelgeuse Romanée-Conti.
In the name of the Witch of Vanity,
for your resolve and steadfast will,
I grant you the title of Sloth.
Do you think I desire such a title?
There is only one thing I desire right now:
peace for that mother and her child!
Love...
How wonderful.
This lie you utter...
is a warmth that can never come to pass!
Hey, listen...
I showed up here, I'm standing here,
and you're just gonna ignore me?
What are you thinking?
No...
Regulus Corneas!
It pisses me off!
There's no way you should be
chosen by the Witch Factor,
but you're holding on to it with no
regard for the payment it requires?
I don't care what you say! I will—
A repetition draw.
While they're locked in a stalemate,
something should be happening
with the other two.
You're saying we should leave here?
But look at what Geuse is
putting himself through!
It's debatable whether or not the strength
of one's will could have affected the outcome.
Then can't we just stand here and watch?
I want to—
It looks like even your insufficient brain
has realized which is the wiser choice.
Change of location.
We're moving to where you
and your mother fled.
No! No, Mother!
Please, Emilia. I'll be
right back, so just...
No! You can't!
You have the same look on
your face that Geuse did!
Don't leave me! Don't leave me behind!
I won't lie or break my promises anymore!
I'll be good! I'll be a good girl!
Emilia...
Emilia... Emilia...
Mother Fortuna...
Mother Fortuna... was my real mother.
I love you.
Fortuna-sama!
Archi, are the villagers safe?
The news is not good.
The men are fighting the people
who arrived with the bishop.
If we stay in the forest,
we'll be found eventually.
They're after...
The seal, right?
How did they find out about it?
Even that woman...
Fine. I'll be right there.
No, we will fight.
You must take Emilia
and leave the forest!
And what happens if I run away now?!
If they get their hands on the seal,
the world will end this time!
I'm sorry you had to go through
all this to protect us.
Please don't say that!
Who would show such disdain
for a family member?!
I'm sorry.
Emilia...
I have to go and fulfill a very
important duty to protect everyone.
So I have to leave for a
little while, all right?
No, Mother! I... I...
Please do as I say.
I want you to leave this forest with Archi.
Fortuna-sama... I—
Archi...
It's a bit early,
but I'm entrusting you with the
mission of the forest dwellers.
Please take Emilia away from here.
This world isn't easy to live in,
but I know there's hope.
I'm sure of it.
I can't! I must stay with everyone until—
Take Emilia.
Please.
She's the beloved daughter of
my brother, his wife, and myself.
It's not fair.
You know I can't refuse
when you tell me that.
I'm sorry.
We're unfair, but please forgive us.
Emilia...
No! I'm staying! I want to stay with you!
Please! Please! I don't...
I don't want to be alone!
You will never be alone.
I will always be right there with you.
In the memories that come forth
when you close your eyes...
In dreams, where you hug
yourself and feel warm...
In the echoes you hear when
you shout into the sky...
I will always be with you.
I'm with you forever and ever.
You're lying... You're lying!
You're a liar, Mother!
Emilia, I promise.
You and I will always be together.
I'll promise you that right now.
Really? You'll stay with me?
Yes, really.
More than anyone, Emilia...
Lia... I love you more than
anyone else in this world.
Mother Fortuna...
I love you too, Mother.
I love you!
I love you... I love you, Mother Fortuna.
I love you so much... so much... so much!
Lia, I love you.
I love you, Emilia.
Why? Why did this happen?
Because I broke my promise and left my room?
No! It's not your fault at all!
It's no one's fault!
They why? Why do we have to leave?
Should I have stayed locked
up in my room forever?
Then no one would leave,
and everyone could stay together?
You're wrong, Emilia!
Was I bad?
Is that why everyone hates me,
and I end up alone?
No! That's not true, Emilia!
No one hates you!
Everything in this world
exists to bless you!
Th-The Black Serpent?
The crucible of disease...
The plague-bearing mabeast?
Fula!
Huma!
Archi?
It's nothing. I'm fine.
Everything is... fine.
Emilia... See the white flowers
between those two trees?
Uh-huh.
Can you run toward those flowers?
Run through them, and keep running straight.
I can... I can run.
But...
Don't worry, Emilia. You won't be alone.
Archi...
Now, run!
Don't look back, no matter what you hear!
Yes, that's right.
Just keep running.
Just like the way you always
give us the run-around.
You think I'm going to let you go?
Fortuna-sama...
I know your daughter will be just fine.
Even after... all this...
Look, why don't you just
admit that it's hopeless?
In the end, that's all there was to
your resolve, your determination, and all that.
It's not like I'm doing
this because I'm a sadist.
It just looks like I'm tormenting
you because you're weak.
Do not criticize him too harshly,
Bishop Corneas.
You are more special and perfect than anyone,
and that makes you wonderful...
And they are also wonderful
in their imperfection.
You just keep giving me more work
to do, you incompetent fool.
Al Fula!
Hang on, Geuse!
Fortuna-sama... Is Emilia-sama—
I sent her out of the forest with Archi,
thanks to you.
That is... good to hear...
There's nothing good about it!
Who the hell do you think
you are, coming back here?
I was about to crush his head under my foot!
Me!
What gives you the right,
who gave you permission,
to interfere with me, me, me, me, me?!
Wait, Bishop Corneas.
Huh? What was that, Pandora-sama?
Calm your anger.
I will not allow you to kill them here.
Do you feel nothing when
you see the two of them?
Did you just order me to calm my anger?
Don't get cocky with that
unassuming attitude, woman!
No...
That's what happens when
you mouth off to me.
Don't interfere with me!
Don't interrupt when I'm talking!
Fortuna-sama, please run—
Don't be a fool.
I left Emilia to come back here.
But why would you...
To keep you from dying.
And so that if you did die,
I'd be by your side.
If you were no longer in this world,
if you stopped coming to this forest,
what would I have to wait for?
I couldn't endure such a long
time without you. I'm too weak.
You... are not weak.
I am!
I was only acting tough in
front of you and Emilia.
Tch!
You wanna ignore me that long and
then have fun on your own? Fine!
I'll crush you both into
nothing but a pool of blood!
I told you to wait, Bishop Corneas.
I will forgive all of your violent
actions and rash outbursts.
My goal in bringing you here
has already been fulfilled.
You are free to leave now.
You brought me here, but now you're
satisfied, so you're telling me to leave?!
What kind of fool do you think I—
I see. Then I will take it upon myself.
Bishop Corneas should not be here.
He is in his own mansion,
surrounded by his wives.
Wai—
I've sent the noisy young man away.
Now we can talk at leisure.
Can I ask one thing first?
Didn't you get blown to
pieces and die earlier?
I'm sorry?
Perhaps your eyes deceived you?
Now that Bishop Corneas is gone,
naturally, the results of
his actions are gone, too.
Th-This is...
But I will not rewrite your being
overtaken by the Sloth Witch Factor.
I wish to commend you on your behavior,
and the behavior of this
woman who came back for you.
Fortuna-sama!
Let us defeat her together!
Right now, we must do what
we can for Emilia-sama!
Freeze the fluctuation
of time itself to white,
Demon Ice of antiquity that brings
eternal sleep to the soul!
My life, my mission, all of my deep love...
Here and now, for this very moment!
Now, come.
Hold me to you and let me feel
the extent of your resolve.
The Day Betelgeuse Laughed
Mother Fortuna...
Geuse... Archi...
I have to... I have to do something, too.
Bring the key and seal here.
Seal?
If that's that you want,
I'll just give it to you.
It's where that thing is...
But...
The fairies?
Are you showing me?
The seal... is that way?
I can save Mother and everyone else?
I want to be with you all again!
I'll be a good girl!
Welcome.
I've been waiting for you.